<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Technology | HarmsSite]]></title>
  <link href="http://harmstyler.github.io/blog/categories/technology/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://harmstyler.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-14T08:56:14-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://harmstyler.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Tyler Harms]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skype version 6]]></title>
    <link href="http://harmstyler.github.io/2012/11/skype-version-6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://harmstyler.github.io/2012/11/skype-version-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="pull-right"><img title="MessageViewVersion" src="http://f.cl.ly/items/2f1o400V1s2P3k2H0x0r/Screen%20Shot%202012-11-01%20at%209.53.36%20AM.png" alt="Message View Version" width="352" height="229" /></div>


<p>I recently updated to Skype 6 and found something interesting out. My style package that worked in Skype 5 would not work in Skype 6. With some digging, we found out that in order to make your Skype 5 style work in Skype 6 you need to update the <code>MessageViewVersion</code> to version 7 (I have no idea why). So, with that, have fun updating your Skype to the latest version while still getting use out of your favorite Skype theme.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EZ Publish with Sublime]]></title>
    <link href="http://harmstyler.github.io/2012/06/ez-publish-with-sublime/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://harmstyler.github.io/2012/06/ez-publish-with-sublime</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="pull-right"><img title="Sublime Text icon" src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/hs_blog_content/images/sublime_text_icon_2181-150x150.png" alt="Sublime Text icon" width="150" height="150" /></div>


<p>A while back I fell in love with <a title="Sublime Text 2" href="http://bit.ly/MHuK34" target="_blank">Sublime Text 2</a> and its' many advantages over TextMate. What it lacked however was any real support for the eZ Publish templating language (no different than TextMate). What I wanted was a simple editor that offered variable and method highlighting equivalent to a nice IDE like PHPStorm. I was originally using the Smarty package for TextMate (you can use any TextMate package in Sublime), but that does not offer a lot of method highlighting support for eZ. So what I decided to do was use the Smarty package as a template for adding more language support for eZ Publish. What I have is far from complete; I usually only add to it when I use a method that is not already supported. You can find it out on <a title="ez sublime on GitHub" href="http://bit.ly/N4eTcp" target="_blank">GitHub</a>. It is my hope that there are some eZ Publish devs out there that really enjoy Sublime as I do and want to help me grow the package. Remember, it is far from complete, but nonetheless, I really hope that you enjoy the language highlighting, and if you do feel free to contribute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
