<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Javascript on Tyler Harms</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/categories/javascript/</link><description>Recent content in Javascript on Tyler Harms</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmstyler.me/categories/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mixing AngularJS and Symfony</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2014/mixing-angular-and-symfony/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2014/mixing-angular-and-symfony/</guid><description>&lt;p>I enjoy being a PHP Developer. PHP is a very flexible language and Symfony2 is
a modern framework that forces many SOLID habits on developers. I also enjoy
working with AngularJS. AngularJS makes Javascript fun and much easier to work
with. Moreover, much like Symfony2, it forces good habits on developers. Getting
the two to work together, however, can be a little bit of a chore if not careful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>jQuery Animate Body Scroll For All Browsers</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/jquery-animate-body-for-all-browsers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/jquery-animate-body-for-all-browsers/</guid><description>It turns out that when trying to use jQuery&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>animate&lt;/code> to &lt;code>scrollTop&lt;/code> on the main body of an html document different browsers require different targets to scroll to. Webkit requires targeting the &lt;code>body&lt;/code> of the document while all other browsers that I know of use &lt;code>html&lt;/code>.</description></item><item><title>IE10 Conditional Comments</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/ie10-conditional-comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/ie10-conditional-comments/</guid><description>Let me start by saying that I was very excited by IE10. Internet Explorer 10 was supposed to be the premier IE web browser. Microsoft was so confident that they created a browser that could meet modern standards that they dropped conditional comments in IE10. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about developing for IE, just know that it sucks; it was, however, aleviated some by conditional comments that allowed for custom styles/js/whatever for IE versions.</description></item></channel></rss>