<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Symfony2 on Tyler Harms</title>
    <link>https://harmstyler.me/categories/symfony2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Symfony2 on Tyler Harms</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://harmstyler.me/categories/symfony2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract Time Stamped Entity in Symfony2</title>
      <link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2014/abstract-time-stamped-entity-in-symfony2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2014/abstract-time-stamped-entity-in-symfony2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite features of Ruby on Rails is that all models are timestamped by default. Ruby on Rails, of course, opts for convention over configuration. Symfony2, on the other hand, opts for configuration over convention. Anyone who has worked with Symfony2 can speak to the mass of config files that exist in a project. I can understand, therefore, why timestamped models (entities) are not a feature in Symfony2. In this post I will show how to add timestamp all your Symfony2 entities. For this post, I chose to use Doctrine as my ORM, so all code show directly relates to Doctrine and Symfony2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symfony2 Coding Standards</title>
      <link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/symfony2-coding-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2013/symfony2-coding-standards/</guid>
      <description>With eZ Publish moving to Symfony2, I found that I was in need of learning some new coding standards. I never really looked into PHP CodeSniffer while doing eZ Publish development (most of my code was in the templates), so I never really thought about PHP CodeSniffer as an option until starting work with Symphony2. To the point, I just wanted to share the Symfony2 PHP CodeSniffer Coding Standard on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>