<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo on Tyler Harms</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/categories/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo on Tyler Harms</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>tyler.harms@gmail.com (Tyler Harms)</managingEditor><webMaster>tyler.harms@gmail.com (Tyler Harms)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:40:52 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://harmstyler.me/categories/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Enhanced Image Rendering in Hugo</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2026/hugo-render-image/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:40:52 -0600</pubDate><author>tyler.harms@gmail.com (Tyler Harms)</author><guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2026/hugo-render-image/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://harmstyler.me/img/hugo-logo-wide.svg"
 alt="Alt"
 title="Hugo Logo"
 
 loading="lazy"
 decoding="async"
 &gt;
One of the things I love about Hugo is its flexibility when it comes to Markdown rendering. While the default behavior
for images is usually enough, I found myself wanting more control. Specifically the ability to add CSS classes
or wrap images in links without resorting to raw HTML in my Markdown files (as hugo raises warnings about this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this, I started using a custom &lt;code&gt;render-image.html&lt;/code&gt; template. It allows me to stay in &amp;ldquo;Markdown mode&amp;rdquo; while
still getting the benefits of optimized, flexible image output.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Pass Variables to a Partial Template in Hugo</title><link>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2019/how-to-pass-variables-to-a-partial-template-in-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 21:05:43 -0500</pubDate><author>tyler.harms@gmail.com (Tyler Harms)</author><guid>https://harmstyler.me/posts/2019/how-to-pass-variables-to-a-partial-template-in-hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I want to keep my code as DRY as is feasible for the given project. In a Hugo project, that&amp;rsquo;s where the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/templates/partials/"&gt;Partial&lt;/a&gt; templates come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partials are smaller, context-aware components in your list and page templates that can be used economically to keep your templating DRY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partials, however, have one serious limitation, they&amp;rsquo;re cached during the build of a given page (or scope). Once a partial has been created, no outside logic can adjust what the partial returns (for the page). This makes the build very fast. But, prevents modifications to the partial if so desired. Imagine a scenario where a partial defines a DOM ID and you want to include the partial twice on the page. In that scenario you&amp;rsquo;ll end up with a duplicated id on the page.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>